Guide to the Collection of Theses from the Faculty of Arts and Science, Department of Economics MC.119
New York University Archives
Collection of Masters Theses from the Faculty of Arts and Science, Department of Economics
1971-1979
New York University Archives
New York University. Department of Economics
Rizzo, Emily
MC.119
5 Linear Feet (10 boxes)
This collection contains a selection of masters theses written by students from the Department of Economics between 1971 and 1979.
Arrangement
The materials were arranged chronologically at the time of accession. They are currently arranged by year and, within each year, alphabetically by the last name of the author. A list of thesis authors and titles may be found at the Archives. Each box is labeled with the year(s) and the range of first letters of authors' last names in that box. For example: 1971-1973, A-F.
Provenance
These materials were accessioned on February 26, 1985, and donated by Emily Rizzo, a staff member in the Department of Economics.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains a selection of masters theses written by students from the Department of Economics between 1971 and 1979. A full list of thesis authors and titles may be found at the Archives. This collection does not contain all graduate theses written by students but is, rather, a selection that was collected by the Department during this time period.
Access restrictions
Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
History of the Economics Department
Undergraduate courses in Political Economy and Finance were being offered at NYU as early as 1846 as part of the Political Science Department's curriculum. In 1895, Political Economy and Finance professor Frank M. Colby became the sole faculty member of the newly formed Graduate School Department of Economics. Undergraduate courses in economics continued to be offered solely by the Department of Political Science until 1912, when an undergraduate Department of Economics was established.
Earning a masters degree in economics at NYU in the 1970s required the completion of 32 credits as well as a masters thesis. The thesis was usually written under the supervision of an advisor as the primary goal of a course entitled "Reading and Research in Economics." The Chairman of the Economics Department during the time these theses were produced was Dr. M. Ishaq Nadiri. Most of the theses are signed as having been approved by the students' faculty advisors. Some of these names can be found as access points.
The Department of Economics now offers undergraduate, masters, and doctoral degrees.
Masters theses; Economics.; Leontief, Wassily, 1906-1999; Rizzo, Emily; Backman, Jules, 1910-1982; Fabricant, Robert
- Theses (A-F), 1971-1973 (Box 1)
- Theses (G-Y), 1973 (Box 2)
- Theses, 1974 (Box 3)
- Theses, 1975 (Box 4)
- Theses (A-E), 1976-1977 (Box 5)
- Theses (A-B), 1977-1978 (Box 6)
- Theses (C-Y), 1978 (Box 7)
- Theses (A-G), 1979 (Box 8)
- Theses (K-Z), 1979 (Box 9)
- Theses, Undated (Box 10)